我杀了人
就把枪丢进泰晤士河
RAY. ; After I killed them,
I dropped the gun
in the Thames,
在汉堡王的厕所里把手洗干净
washed the residue
off me hands in the
bathroom of a Burger King,
再走回家等指示
and walked home
to await instructions.
不久之后等到指示了
Shortly thereafter,
the instructions
came through.
他妈的快滚出伦敦
"Get the fuck out of London,
youse dumb fucks.
去布鲁日！
"Get to Bruges."
我连布鲁日在哪儿都不知道
I didn't even know
where Bruges fucking was.
是在比利时
It's in Belgium.
杀手没有假期
布鲁日是个烂地方
RAY. ; Bruges is a shithole.
才不是咧
KEN. ; Bruges is
not a shithole.
布鲁日是个烂地方
Bruges is a shithole.
雷蒙，我们才刚下火车
Ray, we've only
just got off
the fucking train.
能不能了以后再评论布鲁日?
Could we reserve judgment
on Bruges until we've seen
the fucking place?
反正一定是个烂地方
I know it's gonna be
a shithole.
烂地方
(SOFTLY) Shithole.
应该有人订两个房间
I think you have
a couple of rooms booked
姓名是克伦汉和布雷克利
under Cranham and Blakely?
对，但只有订一个房间
Yes. No, we have
one room booked.
不会吧
No
一间双人房
One twin room.
订了两个礼拜
Booked for two weeks.
两个礼拜?
Two weeks!
还有没有房间?
Do you have
another room?
客满了，因为圣诞节
No, I'm afraid
we're fully booked.
圣诞节到处都客满
With Christmas,
everywhere is fully booked.
好吧
Okay.
好漂亮
It's very pretty.
我说真的，不能住这儿
I'm not being funny,
we can't stay here.
等他打电话来再说
We've got to stay here
until he rings.
如果他两个礼拜都不打来呢?
Well, what if
he doesn't ring
for two weeks?
那就住两个礼拜啊
Then we stay here
for two weeks.
住两个礼拜?
For two weeks?
在布鲁日这个蠢地方?
In fucking Bruges?
住这种房间?跟你?
In a room like this?With you?
我才不要
No way!
雷蒙，我很不想这样讲
Ray, I really don't
like to say this...
你不想怎样讲?
You really don't
like to say what?
你知道的
Well... You know?
不准你再提
Fucking bring that up.
你觉得这很好吗?
Do you think
this is good?
我觉得什么很好?
Do I think what's good?
坐船四处游览
You know,
going round in a boat,
looking at stuff.
很好啊
Yes, I do.
这叫观光
It's called "sightseeing."
你看
Oh, look at that.
那里以前是医院
It's a former hospital.
1100年代
From the 1100s.
布鲁日是全比利时
Bruges is the most
well-preserved
medieval town
保存最好的中世纪城镇
in the whole of
Belgium, apparently.
你要不要上去?
Coming up?
上面有什么?
What's up there?
风景啊
The view.
什么风景?
The view of what?
下面的风景?在这里就看得到了
The view of down here?
I can see that from down here.
雷蒙，你这个观光客很烂耶
Ray, you're about
the worst tourist
in the whole world.
肯尼，我在都柏林长大
Ken, I grew up in Dublin.
我爱都柏林
I love Dublin.
如果我是在农场长大的智障
If I'd grown up on a farm
and was retarded,
我可能会喜欢布鲁日
Bruges might impress me.
可惜我不是，所以不喜欢
But I didn't,
so it doesn't.
我想把零钱用掉
Trying to get rid
of me coins.
3块，3块50分，4块
3, 3.50, 4,
4块10分，20分，30分
4.10, 4.20, 4.30,
4块40分，50分，60分
4.40, 4.50, 4.60,
4块70分
4.70,
4块80分
4.80,
4块90分
4.90.
4块90分可以吗?
Will you take 4.90?
门票是5欧元
Entry is 5 euro.
拜托，才差10分钱
Come on, man,
it's only 10 cents.
门票是5欧元
Entry is 5 euro.
工作开心吗?
Happy in your work?
非常开心
Very happy.
我喜欢这里
I like it here.
去过塔顶吗?
MAN: Been to the top
of the tower?
去过
Yeah. Yeah,
去过了，超烂
it's rubbish.
是吗?
It is?
旅游指南说非去不可
The guidebook says
it's a "must-see".
你们不适合上去
Well, you lot
ain't going up there.
是吗?怎么说?
Pardon me? Why?
楼梯超多阶，你们别去比较好
I mean, it's all windy stairs.
I'm not being funny.
你到底想说什么?
What exactly are you
trying to say?
我想说什么?
What exactly
am I trying to say?
你们胖得跟大象一样
Youse are a bunch
of fucking elephants!
你给我…
Right, you...
好了，算了啦，肥猪
Come on, leave it, fatty.
你真没礼貌！
You know, you're just
the rudest man.
太没礼貌了！
The rudest man!
怎么回事?
What's all that about?
他们不上去了
They're not going up there.
换作是我也不会上去
Hey, guys,
I wouldn't go up there.
楼梯超窄的
It's really narrow.
你这个王八蛋！
Screw you, motherfucker!
是美国人吗?
Americans, isn't it?
这才像话嘛，渡假就要这样
Now, this is more like it.
Proper holidays.
给我好朋友来杯好啤酒
One gay beer
for my gay friend,
我普通的就好，因为我很普通
and one normal beer for me,
because I am normal.
这才叫人生
This is the life.
住这里不是要喝酒的
We're not staying here
getting pissed.
听他的话低调观光
We are quietly sightseeing,
like he says,
等他打来指示下一步
and awaiting his call
to see what we do next.
我觉得不如这样吧
This is my vote
on what we should do.
再等一天
We give it another day,
顶多两天
two days, max.
然后报纸如果还是没报导
Then we check
the papers again, and if
there's still nothing in them,
我们就打给他说：
we phone him and say,
哈利，多谢让我们来布鲁日
"Harry, thank you
for the trip to Bruges,
很开心，古迹很美
"it's been very nice,
all the old buildings
and that,
但我们要回伦敦了
"but we're coming back
to London now,
躲到不只有巧克力的乡下
and hide out
in a proper country,"where it isn't all just
fucking chocolates."
我的建议是…
My vote would be
听他的话低调观光
we quietly sightsee,
like he says,
等他打来指示下一步
and await his call
to see what we do next.
甚至不知道是不是让我们来躲的
You don't even know
we're here hiding out.
你在胡说什么?
What are you talking about?
说不定我们有新任务
You don't even know
we're not here on a job.
什么?新任务?
What, on a job?
对
Yeah.
在布鲁日?
Here in Bruges?
对
Yeah.
来布鲁日出任务?
Here in Bruges, on a job?
对
Yeah.
他到底说了什么?
Why? What did he
actually say?
他什么也没说
He didn't actually
say anything.
那你怎么会以为…
Then why do you think
it might be?
我没以为什么
I don't think anything.
但这也太刻意了吧
But it's a bit fucking
over-elaborate, isn't it?
带他去躲起来
"Go take him to hide out."
带他去躲在哪里?
"Go take him to
hide out where?"
他妈的带他躲在布鲁日
"Go take him to hide out
in fucking Bruges."
可以躲在克洛顿啊
You can hide out
in Croydon.
科芬特里也可以
Or Coventry.
这样是有点太刻意了
It is a bit
over-elaborate.
但我们又没枪
But we haven't
got any guns.
哈利在哪儿都弄得到枪
Harry can get guns anywhere.
他今晚不会打来了
He's not gonna ring tonight.
他今晚不会打来了吧！
我们出去
Let's go out.
去哪儿?
Go out where?
酒吧
The pub.
不要
No!
我们出去看看那些中世纪建筑
Let's go out
and have a look
at some of the All the old medieval
buildings and that.
晚上点了灯一定更漂亮
Because I bet they look
even better at night,
all lit up.
搞定！
Yes!
那是格鲁修斯博物馆
That there is called
the Gruuthuse Museum.
名字都好奇怪
They all have
funny names,
don't they?
对，法兰德斯语
Yes, Flemish.
这上面写：
In here it says,
比利时两度庇护被追杀的英王
"The Belgians twice sheltered
fugitive English Kings
1471年和1651年
"from being murdered,
1471 and 1651."
我讨厌历史，你不会吗?
I used to hate history,
didn't you?
都是发生过的事啊
It's all just a load of stuff
that's already happened.
那边在干嘛?
What are they
doing over there?
好像拍什么
They're filming something.
他们在拍侏儒
They're filming midgets!
雷蒙！
Ray!
这一幕你要像小老鼠走来走去
MAN: So, on this scene,
you're supposed to walk like
a little, tiny mouse, yeah?
可以吗?很好
Okay? Great.
雷蒙，我们走啦
Ray, come on, let's go.
干嘛走?他们在拍侏儒耶
My arse, "Let's go."
They're filming midgets.
天哪！你看那个美眉
Oh, my God!
Look at that girl.
超正的
She's gorgeous!
雷蒙，走了啦
Ray, we're going
right now.
门儿都没有
Fuck off, are we!
我来布鲁日没这么兴奋过
This is the best bit
of Bruges so far.
你只会看古迹
You and your buildings.
你好
Hello.
你会讲英语吗?
Do you speak English?
不会
No.
你会啦
Yes, you do.
大家都会
Everybody does.
你们干嘛拍侏儒?
What are you
filming midgets for?
这是荷兰片
It's a Dutch movie.
这场戏是在梦中
It's a dream sequence.
抄袭名导罗吉的威尼斯痴魂
It's a pastiche of
Nicholas Roeg's Don't Look Now.
不是抄袭，而是…
Not a pastiche, but a...
说是向他致意又太夸张了
A"homage" is too strong.
只是表示赞同啦
A"nod of the head"?
你的英语讲得真好
Wow, your English
is very good.
很多侏儒都是自杀的
A lot of midgets
tend to kill themselves.
在比例上算高的啦
A disproportionate amount.
比如奇幻岛，，的赫夫维勒柴
Herve Villechaize,
off of Fantasy Island.
危险地带，，好像也有
I think somebody
off The Time Bandits.
他们一定都是…
I suppose they must
因为个儿小…
get really sad about, like,
…觉得很难过
being really
little and that.
别人的眼光，大家都嘲笑他们
People looking at them
and laughing at them.
辱骂他们
Calling them names.
骂他们矮冬瓜
You know, "shortarse."
还有一个侏儒很有名
There's another famous
刚才没讲到，但我想不起来
midget I'm missing,
but I can't remember.
不是星际大战，，的R2D2
It's not the R2-D2 man.
不，他还活着
No, he's still going.
希望你的侏儒不会自杀
I hope your midget
doesn't kill himself.
不然就拍不成了
Your
dream sequence will be fucked.
他不喜欢人家叫他侏儒
He doesn't like
being called a midget.
叫他小不点比较好
He prefers "dwarf."
这就是我的重点
Well, this is
exactly my point!
大家都叫你侏儒
People go around calling
you a midget
你却要别人叫你小不点
when you
want to be called a dwarf.
难怪会举枪自尽嘛
Of course you're
gonna blow your head off!
我叫雷蒙，你呢?
My name's Ray. What's yours?
克洛伊
Chloe.
你是怎么通过保全那一关的?
How did you get past
the security man?
通过保全那一关
Getting past security men,
是我的工作
it's sort of my job.
你是小偷?
You're a shoplifter?
不是，我不是小偷
(CHUCKLES) No,
not a shoplifter.
这笑话超冷的
It's a good joke, though.
不是
No.
明天陪我吃晚饭
I'll tell you
我再跟你说我是做什么的
what I am
at dinner tomorrow night.
干！
Fuck.
(克洛伊维雷)
他妈的有搞头了！
How fucking cool.
布雷克利先生?
Mr. Blakely?
不是，我是克伦汉
Yes. No, Mr. Cranham.
不对，我是布雷克利
No. Yes. Mr. Blakely. Yes.
有人留话给你
You have a message.
干！
Shit!
第一：你们怎么不在
HARRY. ; Number one,
why aren't you in when
他妈的我叫你们去的地方?
I fucking told you to be in?
第二：这家旅馆的电话
Number two, why doesn't
this hotel
他妈的怎么不能留话?
have phones
with fucking voicemail
还得留话给他妈的柜台小姐?
and not I have to leave
messages with the
fucking receptionist?
第三：我明晚再打去
Number three, you better
fucking be in tomorrow night
他妈的你们最好都在
when I fucking call again
不然你们他妈的就死定了
or there'll be fucking
Hell to pay,
我正在他妈的警告你
I'm fucking
telling you.
哈利
Harry.
(我不是柜台小姐)
(这是我和外子派崔斯合开的)
(玛莉)
他妈的请你关灯好吗?
Would you turn
the fucking light off!
对不起
Sorry, Ken.
他妈的小声一点
Keep the fucking
noise down!
有人心情不好
Someone's in a mood.
你绝对猜不到的
(SOFTLY) You'll
never guess what.
Will you shut your
请你他妈的闭嘴，睡觉啦
fucking mouth, please,
and go to sleep?
对不起
Oh, sorry.
我先拿掉隐形眼镜
Except I've gotta take me
contact lenses out.
我总共…
Altogether,
喝了…
I had
5杯啤酒
five pints of beer
还有6瓶
and six bottles.
不对
No.
6杯啤酒和7瓶
Six pints of beer
and seven bottles.
可是我没醉耶！
And you know what?
I'm not even pissed!
你绝对猜不到的
You'll never guess what, Ken.
肯尼，保证你猜不到
Ken, you'll never guess what.
什么?
What?
我明晚有约会
Got a date for
tomorrow night.
恭喜你啊
I'm very happy for you.
跟一个女生
With a girl.
请你关灯好吗?
Can you turn
the light off, please?
才来布鲁日一天
Only been in Bruges one day,
就约了电影业的女生
got a date with a girl
in the film business,
比利时电影业
the Belgian film business.
他们在拍侏儒的电影
They're doing a film
about a midget.
小姐?
Miss?
玛莉?
Marie?
昨晚留言的事很抱歉
Sorry about the message
last night.
留话的那个人有点…
The man who
left it is a bit of a...
他有点鸡巴…
Well, he's a bit of a...
讨人厌?
Cock?
对，他有点讨人厌鸡巴
Yes. He's a bit of a cock.
早安
Morning.
哈利昨晚打电话来了
Harry called last night.
我们没接到
We missed him.
天哪，他嘴巴真脏
Jeez, he swears a lot,
doesn't he?
今晚不能出去
We're staying in tonight.
无论如何都不行
Whatever happens.
不过…
Except...
不过什么?
Except "hmm" what?
只要一个人留守就好了
Except only one of us
needs to stay in, really.
真的啦
Uh-huh.
是谁要留守?
And which one of us
would that be, now, Ray?
你不是不喜欢布鲁日?
I thought you
didn't like Bruges.
我不喜欢布鲁日，这是烂地方
I don't like Bruges,
it's a shithole.
但我说过我有约会
But I did already say
和比利时电影业的比利时女孩
I had a date with
a Belgian lady in the Belgian film business,
我跟你说过了
which I did already
say about before.
别惹麻烦就好了啦
Just don't get into
any fucking trouble.
我们要低调一点
We're keeping a low profile.
今天早上
And this morning,
还有今天下午
and this afternoon,
都要做我想做的事，懂吗?
we are doing
what I want to do.
懂
Got it?
Of course.
应该和文化有关吧
Which, I presume,
will involve culture.
要在文化和乐趣中找到平衡点
Oh, we shall strike a balance
between culture and fun.
我相信这个平衡点
Somehow I believe, Ken,
that the balance
是比较偏向文化
shall tip
in the favor of culture.
就像一个胖子智障
Like a big, fat,
fucking retarded,
黑人胖女生妞去坐翘翘板
fucking black girl
另一边是…
on a seesaw, opposite
…一个小矮人
a dwarf.
雷蒙，我们是不是说好
(SOFTLY) Ray, did we
or did we not agree
只要我今晚让你去约会
that if I let you
go on your date tonight,
今天就做我想做的事?
we'd do the things
I wanted to do today?
今天要做你想做的事
We are doing the things
that you wanted to do today.
做的时后不准你耍性子
And that we'd do them
without you throwing
a fucking moody,
像糖果掉满地的5岁小孩
like some 5-year-old
who's dropped
all his sweets?
我又没答应要这样
I didn't agree to that.
我尽量配合啦
I'll cheer up.
在那上面，祭台的最顶上
Up there,
the top altar,
有个小玻璃瓶
is a phial
参加圣战的法兰德斯骑士
brought back by
a Flemish knight
从圣地带回来的
from the
Crusades in the Holy Land.
那个玻璃瓶…
And that phial,
你知道里面是什么吗?
do you know what
it's said to contain?
不知道，是什么?
No, what's it
said to contain?
据说是耶稣基督的血
It's said to contain
some drops of
Jesus Christ's blood.
对，这间教堂就是因此而得名
Yeah, that's how
this church got its name.
圣血教堂
Basilica of the Holy Blood.
是吗?
Yeah. Yeah.
对，那里面的血…
And this blood, right,
虽然干掉了
though it's dried blood,
多年来在不同的时间点
at different times
over many years,
据说都又变回液态
they say
it turned back into liquid.
从干掉的血变回液态
Turned back into liquid
from dried blood.
在不同的…
At various times of great
…危机时刻
stress.
是吗?
Yeah?
Yeah.
对，所以说…
So, yeah,
我要去排队摸了，你也一起去
I'm gonna go up
in the queue and touch it,
which is what you do.
是吗?
Yeah?
对，你要来吗?
Yeah. You coming?
非去不可吗?
Do I have to?
Do you have to?
当然不一定
Of course you
don't have to.
那是他妈的耶稣的血
It's Jesus' fucking blood,
isn't it?
你他妈的当然不一定要摸
Of course you
don't fucking have to!
你他妈的当然不一定要摸啦！
Of course you don't
fucking have to!
你这个死小子
You little fucking cunt.
我杀了人，神父
RAY. ; Murder, Father.
雷蒙，你为什么杀人?
PRIEST. ; Why did you
murder someone, Raymond?
为了钱，神父
For money, Father.
为了钱?
For money?
你为钱杀人?
You murdered
someone for money?
是的
Yes, Father.
不是因为生气，没别的原因
Not out of anger,
not out of nothing.
就是为了钱
For money.
雷蒙，你为钱杀谁?
Who did you murder
for money, Raymond?
杀你，神父
You, Father.
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
我说我要杀你，神父
I said you, Father.
你聋了吗?
What, are you deaf?
哈利华特斯要我问后你
Harry Waters says hello.
小男孩
The little boy.
(1.耍任性)
(2.数学考不好)
(3.伤心)
这我满喜欢的
RAY: I quite like this one.
其他都很不协调
All the rest were
rubbish by spastics,
但这幅画得好
but this one's quite good.
内容是什么?
What's that
all about, then?
这是最后审判日
It's Judgment Day,
you know?
是喔
Oh, yeah.
那又是什么?
What's that then?
就是人间的最后一天
Well, it's, you know,
the final day on Earth.
人类犯的罪都要被审判
When mankind will be
judged for all the crimes
诸如此类的事
they've committed and that.
看看谁能上天堂谁能下地狱?
And see who gets
into Heaven and who gets
into Hell and all that?
对
Yeah.
另一个地方是什么?
And what's the other place?
炼狱
Purgatory.
Purgatory?
炼狱是个折衷的地方
Purgatory's kind of like
the in-betweeny one.
给不太烂也不太好的人去的
You weren't really shit,
but you weren't
all that great, either.
像塔腾汉一样
Like Tottenham.
你相信那些?
Do you believe
in all that stuff, Ken?
塔腾汉?
About Tottenham?
最后审判日和来生
The Last Judgment
and the afterlife.
还有罪恶感
Guilt and
原罪
sins and
地狱
Hell and
那些事?
all that?
我不知道，雷蒙
Um...
我不知道我相信什么
KEN: I don't know, Ray.
I don't know what I believe.
你小时后学的事就根深蒂固了
The things you're
taught as a child, they never
really leave you, do they?
比如我相信好好过日子
So, like,
I believe in trying
to lead a good life.
比如老太太买完东西要回家
Like, if there's an old lady,
carrying her shopping home,
我不会帮她提东西
I don't try and help her
carry her shopping,
I don't go that far,
我不会做到那样
but I'll certainly hold the
我是会替她开门啦
door open for her and that,
让她先出去
and let her go out before me.
对，就算你想帮她提东西
Yeah. And anyway,
if you tried to help her
carry her shopping,
她可能只会以为你想抢劫她
she'd probably think
you were just trying
to nick her shopping.
没错
Exactly.
这就是现今的社会
This is the world
we live in today.
同时…
At the same time
在好好过日子的同时
as trying to lead
a good life,
我要认命我杀了人
I have to reconcile myself
with the fact that, yes,
I have killed people.
没有很多人啦
Not many people.
大部分都不是什么好人
Most of them were
not very nice people.
有个人除外
Apart from one person.
是谁?
Who's that?
丹尼亚利班的哥哥
This fellow,
Danny Aliband's brother.
他只是想保护他弟弟
He was just trying
to protect his brother.
跟你我一样，他只是个导护老师
Like you or I would.He was just a lollipop man.
他拿着酒瓶向我走过来
He came at me with a bottle.
你会怎样?我毙了他
What are you gonna do?I shot him down.
可是我觉得…
In my book, though,
抱歉，有人拿酒瓶向你走过来
sorry, someone comes
at you with a bottle,
那是致命的武器，后果他要自负
that is a deadly weapon,
he's gotta take
the consequences.
我心里有数
I know that in my heart.
我也知道他只是想保护他弟弟
I also know that he was
just trying to protect
his brother, you know?
我知道，但用酒瓶也可能杀了你
I know. But a bottle,
that can kill you.
这是你死我活的问题
It's a case of
it's you or him.
如果他赤手空拳就不一样了
If he'd come at you
with his bare hands,
that'd be different.
那就不公平了
That wouldn't
have been fair.
赤手空拳也能杀人
Well, technically,
your bare hands
can kill somebody, too.
那也是致命武器
They can be
deadly weapons, too.
说不定他会空手道
I mean,
what if he knew karate, say?
你说过他是导护老师
You said he was
a lollipop man.
他是导护老师
He was a lollipop man.
导护老师会什么空手道?
What's a lollipop man doing
knowing fucking karate?
我只是随便说说
I'm just saying.
他几岁?
How old was he?
About 50.
50岁上下
What's a 50-year-old
50岁的导护老师会啥空手道?
lollipop man doing
knowing fucking karate?
难道是中国来的导护老师?
What was he,
a Chinese lollipop man?
拜托
Jesus, Ken,
我想说的是…
I'm trying to
talk about...
我知道你想说什么
I know what you're
trying to talk about.
我杀了一个小男孩
I killed a little boy.
你还一直提导护老师
You keep bringing up
fucking lollipop men!
你不是故意杀小男孩的
You didn't mean
to kill a little boy.
我知道我不是故意的
I know I didn't mean to.
但因为我作的抉择
But because of the choices I made and the course
that
我做的事让一个小男孩不在了
I put into action,a little boy
isn't here anymore.
他再也不会回来
And he'll never
be here again.
不会回到这个世上，不是比利时
I mean here in the world,
not here in Belgium.
反正他也不可能来比利时了
Well, he'll never be
here in Belgium,
either, will he?
说不定他长大会想来这里
I mean, he might have
wanted to come here
when he got older.
我不知道为什么
I don't know why.
都是我害的
And that's all because of me.
他是因我而死
He's dead because of me.
我想…
And I'm trying to...
我想释怀，但我做不到
I'm trying to
get me head around it,
but I can't.
我杀了那个小男孩是事实
I will always have
killed that little boy.
永远也忘不了
That ain't ever
going away.
永远忘不了
Ever.
除非…
Unless...
我自我了断
Maybe I go away.
别乱想啦
Don't even think like that.
你很帅
You look good.
有个屁用?
What's it matter anyway?
雷蒙，你是做什么的?
So, what do you do, Raymond?
我…
I
为了钱杀人
shoot people for money.
怎样的人?
What kinds of people?
神父，小孩，还不就那样
Priests. Children.
You know, the usual.
做那一行能赚很多钱吗?
Is there a lot of money
to be made in that
line of business?
杀神父可以，杀小孩就没钱赚
There is in priests.
There isn't in children.
克洛伊，你是做什么的?
So what is it
you do, Chloe?
卖可卡因和海洛因给比利时剧组
I sell cocaine and heroin
to Belgian film crews.
真的吗?
Do you?
我看起来像吗?
Do I look like I do?
其实满像的
You do, actually.
我看起来像会杀人吗?
Do I look like
I shoot people?
不像
No.
只会杀小孩啦
Just children.
我今天看到你那个侏儒
I saw your midget today.
那个混蛋连个招呼都不打
Little prick didn't
even say hello.
他吃太多K他命了
Well, he's on
a lot of ketamine.
那是什么?
What's that?
马的镇静剂
Horse tranquilizer.
马的镇静剂?
A horse tranquilizer?
他哪来的?
Where'd he get that?
我卖给他的
I sold it to him.
不能卖马的镇静剂给侏儒啦
You can't sell
horse tranquilizers
to a midget!
我觉得这会是一部好电影
This movie,
I think it's gonna be
a very good one.
到现在才有在布鲁日拍的好电影
There's never been
a classic movie made
in Bruges until now.
想也知道没有，这是个烂地方
Of course there hasn't,
it's a shithole.
布鲁日是我的家乡
Bruges is my hometown, Ray.
还是烂地方啊
Well, it's still a shithole.
才不是烂地方
It's not a shithole.
怎样?连侏儒都要嗑药才待得住
What? Even midgets have to
take drugs to stick it.
好吧
Okay.
那…
So,
你侮辱了我的家乡
you've insulted
my hometown.
你表现得很好
You're doing
very well, Raymond.
顺便讲几个比利时笑话给我听吧
Why don't you tell me
some Belgian jokes
while you're at it?
我不知道比利时笑话
I don't know
any Belgian jokes.
就算我知道也不会笨到…
And if I did,
I think I'd have
the good sense not to...
等一下
Hey, hang on.
比利时最近很多虐杀小孩事件?
Is Belgium
where there were all those
child abuse murders lately?
那我知道比利时笑话了
Then I do know
a Belgian joke.
比利时以什么闻名?
What's Belgium famous for?
巧克力和虐童
Chocolates and child abuse.
发明巧克力只是为了引诱小孩
And they only invented
the chocolates to
get to the kids.
干嘛?
What?
有个被虐杀的女孩是我的朋友
One of the girls
they murdered was
a friend of mine.
对不起
I'm sorry, Chloe.
那个被虐杀的女孩不是我朋友啦
One of the girls
they murdered wasn't
a friend of mine.
我只是想看你难过
I just wanted to
make you feel bad.
你上当了
And it worked.
被我骗了
Quite well.
真过分
Fucking unbelievable.
什么事过分?
What's fucking
unbelievable?
你在跟我讲话吗?
Are you talking to me?
他停顿了，虽然他超想揍人的
(SOFTLY) He pauses,
even though he should
just hit the cunt.
他还回嘴咧
And he repeats.
对，我就是在跟你说话
Yes, I am talking to you.
什么事过分?
What's fucking unbelievable?
告诉你什么事过分啦
Well, I'll tell you what's
fucking unbelievable, shall I?
对着我和我女朋友的脸上吐烟
Blowing cigarette smoke
straight into myself
and my girlfriend's face.
太过分了
That's fucking unbelievable!
这里是吸烟区
This is the smoking section.
我不管是不是吸烟区
I don't care if it's
the smoking section.
她直接对着我脸上吐烟
All right?
She directed it
right in my face, man.
我可不想被你的傲慢害死
I don't wanna die just because
of your fucking arrogance.
Uh-huh.
越南人以前也这样讲
Isn't that what the
Vietnamese used to say?
越南人?
Vietnamese?
干嘛扯到越南人?
What are you
talking about, the Vietnamese?
讲这种话根本不合逻辑
That statement makes
no fucking sense at all.
很合逻辑啊，越南人
Yes it does.
The Vietnamese!
多讲几次也不会合逻辑
Well, saying it over
and over ain't gonna make
any more sense out of it.
我和我女朋友吸你朋友的二手烟
How does the Vietnamese
have any relevance whatsoever to myself and my girlfriend
having to breathe
关越南人什么事?
your friend's
cigarette smoke?
告诉我…
Tell me how saying...
我替约翰蓝侬扁你啦，死美国佬
That's for John Lennon,
you Yankee fucking cunt!
酒瓶?
A bottle?
不用麻烦了
No, don't bother.
对，我们要走了
We're leaving.
我没打女人
I don't hit women!
我从来不打女人
I would never
hit a woman, Chloe!
拿酒瓶想打我的女人例外
I'd hit a woman
who was trying to
hit me with a bottle!
那不一样，那叫自卫
That's different.
That's self-defense,
isn't it?
或是会空手道的女人
Or a woman
who could do karate.
大部分的女人我都不会打
I'd never hit
a woman generally, Chloe.
别误会了
Don't think that.
天哪，你好漂亮
God, you're pretty.
我要去打电话
I have to make a call.
不会吧
Oh, no.
你不要我了，因为我打了女人
You've gone off me, now,
haven't you? Just because
I hit that fucking cow.
喂?
Hello?
你他妈的昨天去哪里?
HARRY. ; Where the fuck
were you yesterday?
我们只是出去吃晚饭，才半小时
We just popped out for
some dinner, Harry. We only
popped out for half an hour.
是吗?你们吃什么?
Yeah? What'd you have?
晚饭吗?
For dinner?
对
Yeah.
披萨，去必胜客
Pizza, at Pizza Hut.
好吃吗?
Was it nice?
还不错，就是必胜客嘛
Yeah, it was all right.
I don't know.
It was Pizza Hut.
跟英国一样
The same as in England.
对，这就是国际全球化
Well, that's globalization,
isn't it?
雷蒙也在吗?
Is Ray
there with you?
他在厕所
He's in the toilet.
他听得见吗?
Can he hear?
听不见
No.
他在干嘛?
What's he doing?
什么意思?
What do you mean?
他在小号或大号?
Is he doing a wee or a poo?
我不知道，哈利，门关着
I don't know, Harry,
the door's closed.
叫他出去办事半小时
Send him out on an errand
for half an hour,
但别让他起疑心
but don't
make it sound suspicious.
雷蒙?你去酒吧半小时好吗?
Ray? Why don't you
go out down to the pub
for half an hour?
对，我知道我说你不能去
Yeah, yeah, I know
I said you couldn't,
但你去玩一下嘛
but might as well
enjoy ourselves, eh?
我不知道哪里能打保龄球
No, I don't know if
they've got bowling anywhere.
你去问问看
Could have a look.
好，再见
Yeah, see you.
他走了
Yeah. He's gone.
你跟他说什么?
What'd you say to him?
我叫他去喝杯酒，出去透透气
I said, " Why don't you go
have a drink, you say
you've been cooped up?"
他怎么说?
What did he say?
他说好
Said, yeah, he would.
他可能要去问哪里有保龄球馆
And he might go have
a look to see if there's
a bowling alley around.
他刚才是在尿尿?
Was he just having a wee?
大概吧，应该是
Yeah, I think so.
I assume so.
所以他不介意?
Sure he didn't mind?
对，他早就想出去了
No, he was glad
to get out.
他真的走了吗?
He's definitely gone?
对，他甩上门了
Yeah, yeah,
he slammed the door.
甩门不表示就走了，去门外看看
That don't mean he's gone.
Go check outside the door.
哈利，他走了啦
Harry, he's definitely gone.
你知不知道布鲁日没保龄球馆?
You realize there are no
bowling alleys in Bruges?
我知道，他还是想去找
I realize that, Harry.
The boy wanted to
have a look anyway.
难不成要盖中世纪保龄球馆?
What are they gonna have,
a medieval fucking
bowling alley?
我说了他就是想出去嘛
As I say, I think
he was just glad
to get out and about.
他看到运河开心吗?
So, is he having
a nice time, seeing
all the canals and that?
我就很喜欢那里
I had a lovely time
when I was there.
好多运河和古迹建筑
All the canals and the
old buildings and that.
你几时来过?
When were you here?
我7岁的时后
When I was seven.
最后一次快乐的假期
Last happy holiday
I fucking had.
你们有去游运河吗?
Have you been on
a canal trip, yet?
有
Yeah.
有没有去走旧石头路?
Have you been down,
like, all the old
cobbled streets and that?
有
Yeah.
那里像童话故事一样吧?
It's like a fairytale,
isn't it, that place?
对
Yeah.
好多教堂，哥德式教堂
With the churches and that.
They're Gothic.
对
Yeah.
是哥德式吗?
Is it Gothic?
对
Yeah.
他玩得很开心?
So he's having
a really nice time?
我是玩得很开心
Well, I'm having
a really nice time.
我不确定他喜不喜欢
I'm not sure if it's
really his cup of tea.
什么?
What?
我不确定他喜不喜欢
You know, I'm not sure
if it's really his thing.
怎么会不喜欢?
What do you mean,
"It's not really his thing"?
他怎么可能不喜欢?
What's that supposed to mean,
"It's not really his thing"?
这话他妈的是什么意思?
What the fuck is that
supposed to mean?
没什么
Nothing, Harry.
那里像他妈的童话故事一样
It's a fairytale
fucking town, isn't it?
怎么会有人不喜欢童话故事?
How can a fairytale town
not be somebody's
fucking thing?
运河，桥，石头路和教堂
How can all those canals
and bridges and cobbled
streets and those churches,
他妈的美丽的童话故事城市
all that beautiful
fucking fairytale stuff,
怎么会有人他妈的不喜欢?
how can that not be
somebody's fucking thing, eh?
我想说的是…
What I think
I meant to say was...
那里还有天鹅吗?
Is the swan still there?
Yeah, the swan's...
有，还有天鹅
How can fucking swans
not fucking
怎么会有人不喜欢天鹅?
be somebody's
fucking thing, eh?
怎么可能?
How can that be?
我想说的是…
What I think
I meant to say was,
他刚来的时后不太喜欢
when he first arrived,
he wasn't quite sure about it.
刚下火车有条4线道大马路
You know, there's that big,
dual carriageway when you
get off the train?
你上次来的时后可能没有
It mightn't have been
here when you were
here last, Harry.
但他一进到旧城区
Well, as soon as he got into,
like, the old town proper,
看到运河和桥梁
and he saw the canals
and the bridges and,
还有天鹅，他就他妈的就爱上这里了
you know, the swans and that,well, he just
fucking loved it then.
怎么看都不过瘾
Couldn't get enough of it,
中世纪的古迹
the medieval part of town.
只是…
It was just that initial,
刚开始的大马路吓到他了
dual carriageway thing sort of
put him off for a second.
我不记得有大马路
Don't know if I remember
a dual carriageway.
是最近才有的吧
Must be recent.
没扫兴吧?
Hasn't spoilt it, has it?
没有…
No, no, no,
只是刚开始而已
it's just that
initial thing.
你知道吗?
And you know what?
我们走在街道上
As we were walking
through the streets,
还有…
there was
冰冷的薄雾笼罩着建筑物
this sort of
freezing fog hanging
over everything,
看起来更像童话故事了
and it made it
look almost like
a fairytale or something.
你知道他跟我说什么吗?
And he turned to me,
do you know what he said?
他说什么?
What'd he say?
他说：肯尼，我知道我醒着
He said, " Ken, I know
I'm awake,
但我觉得好像在作梦
but I feel
like I'm in a dream."
是吗?他那样讲?
Yeah? He said that?
对
Yeah.
应该是美梦吧?
Meaning, like,
in a good dream?
对，当然是美梦
Yeah. Of course,
like in a good dream.
那就好
Oh, good.
很高兴他喜欢那里
I'm glad he likes it there.
幸好我们还能让他开心
I'm glad we were able
to give him something.
给他好印象，他毕竟不是坏孩子
Something good and happy.
Because he wasn't
a bad kid, was he?
他不是坏孩子吧?
He wasn't a bad kid,
was he?
记下这个地址
Listen, take down
this address.
朗斯察17号
Raamstraat 17.
是“朗，，，不是”郎
That's "Raam," like "Ram,"
but with an extra "a."
朗斯察17号
Raamstraat 17.
记好没?
You got that?
好了，朗斯察17号
Yes, Raamstraat 17.
好，明早9点会有人在那里等
Good. There'll be a man
there tomorrow morning
at 9.;00,
他叫尤利
his name's Yuri.
尤利
Yuri.
他会给你枪
He'll give you the gun.
明天3，4点办完事以后
Ring me on the public phone
at Jimmy Driscoll's
用公共电话打给我
about 3.;00 or 4.;00 tomorrow,
after it's done.
办完什么事?
After what's done?
你是笨蛋吗?
Are you being thick?
不是
No.
我喜欢雷蒙，他是个好人
Listen, I like Ray.
He was a good bloke,
但他在办正事时误杀了一个小孩
but when it all comes
down to it, you know,he blew the head off
a little fucking kid.
他是你介绍的
And you brought him in, Ken.
你自己的烂摊子要自己收
So if the buck
don't stop with him,
where does it stop?
肯尼?
Ken?
你自己的烂摊子要自己收
If the buck
don't stop with him,
where does it stop?
我会收的，超简单
It stops with me, Harry.
That's an easy one.
别生气，肯尼
Look, don't get shirty, Ken.
很高兴能在他死前为他做点事
Listen, I'm just glad that
I was able to do something
for the boy before he went.
做什么事?
Do what for the boy?
让他去看看布鲁日
You know, have him
get to see Bruges.
我死前也想再看看布鲁日
I'd like to go to see
Bruges again before I die.
他是怎么说的?好像在作梦?
What was it he said
again about... Yeah,
"It's like a dream."
我知道我醒着
"I know I'm awake,
但我觉得好像在作梦
but I feel like
I'm in a dream."
对
Yeah.
他死了再跟我说
Give me a call
when he's dead.
她是我女朋友，王八蛋！
That's my fucking girlfriend,
you asshole.
艾瑞克，你在干嘛?
Eirik, what are you doing?
你打哪儿来的?
Where are you from, fucker?
我是爱尔兰人
Ireland, originally.
你跑来比利时搞别人的女朋友?
And you think it's okay
to come over to Belgium and fuck another man's girl?
我不知道她有男朋友
Look, I didn't know
she had a boyfriend,
all right?
我也没搞她，不信你问她
And I haven't fucked her,
anyway. Ask her.
我只用手摸而已
I'd only put me hand on it.
艾瑞克，把枪放下！
Eirik, put the gun down!
跪下来把嘴张开
Get down on your knees
and open your mouth.
别做傻事啊
Don't start being silly.
给我跪下…
Get down on your...
小混混怎么突然都变得这么娘?
Exactly at what point
was it that all skinheads
suddenly became poofs?
以前的小混混都去殴打
Used to be,
you were a skinhead,
you just went around
beating up
12岁的巴基坦小孩
Pakistani 12-year-olds.
现在却变得这么娘
Now it seems a prerequisite
to be a fucking bum-boy!
拿刀也没用啦
That's not gonna
help you, man.
雷蒙，那把枪里只有空包弹
Ray, there's only
blanks in that gun.
艾瑞克，不要！
Eirik, don't!
谁才娘啊！
Now who's the
fucking bum-boy?
你这个他妈的臭娘们！
You, you fucking bum-boy!
克洛伊?
Chloe,
这是怎么回事?
what exactly
is going on here?
我看不见了
I can't see!
你当然看不见
Of course you can't
fucking see!
我刚才用空包弹打你的眼睛
I just shot
a blank in your fucking eyes!
这个人是你男朋友?
Is this fella your boyfriend?
不是
No.
我是说…
I mean,
他以前是
he used to be.
他来这里干嘛?
Well, what's he doing here?
我们…
We...
我们偶尔会抢观光客
We rob tourists,
sometimes.
我就知道没这么好的事  他冲进来抓奸…
I fucking knew
it was too good
to be true!
我就知道你不会跟我上床
I knew you'd have never
shagged me, normally.
不是这样啦
No! That's not true, I...
今晚我取消了，我叫他今晚别来
I called it off tonight.
I told him not
to come tonight.
你今晚还来干嘛?
Why did you come tonight?
克洛伊，我真的看不见了
EIRIK: Chloe,
I can't see,
I swear it!
别再像娘们鬼叫了啦
Stop whingeing
like a big gay baby.
我好几个月没打炮了
I haven't had
a shag in months!
克洛伊，我这只眼睛看不见了
I can't see out of this eye,
Chloe!
我要去医院！
I have to go
to the hospital!
我载你去
I'll drive you.
好极了，坏了我的好事
Great! Now the whole
night's ruined!
不！
No!
你可以留下来
You can stay if you want.
只是不知道要弄多久
I just don't know
how long I'll be.
我就知道你这种女人
I just knew someone like you
不会喜欢我这种男人
would never like
someone like me.
天哪！
God
我就知道
I just knew.
什么叫我这种女人?
What do you mean,
someone like me?
就是好女人啊
You know, someone nice.
打电话给我
Call me.
求求你
Please.
克洛伊！
EIRIK: Chloe!
挖到宝了
Cha-ching!
(空包弹)
(实弹)
你有什么问题吗?
Have you got some
sort of problem?
没有，没问题
No, no problem.
20分钟内喝4杯啤酒
Four beers
in 20 minutes.
没问题
No problem.
滚啦
Fuck off.
一杯啤酒和一杯红酒
JIMMY: Beer and a red wine.
我马上回来
I'll be back.
电影拍得如何?
How's the movie going?
那是欧洲人剥削劳工拍的烂片啦
It's a jumped-up
Eurotrash piece of
rip-off fucking bullshit.
拍得不好吗?
Like, in a bad way?
你女朋友很漂亮
Your girlfriend's
very pretty.
她不是我女朋友
She ain't my girlfriend.
她是妓女，我刚才叫的
She's a prostitute
I just picked up.
我都不知道布鲁日有妓女
Didn't know there were
any prostitutes in Bruges.
找对地方就有了
You just have to look
in the right places.
去妓院找
Brothels are good.
你叫的妓女很漂亮
Well, you've picked up
a very pretty prostitute.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是美国人?
You from the States?
对
Yeah.
别排挤美国人哦
But don't hold it
against me.
我尽量
I'll try not to.
尽量别大声或讲蠢话
Just try not to say
anything too loud or crass.
你在喝闷酒?
Hey-ho. Drowning
your sorrows, huh?
闷什么?
What sorrows?
难过你又老又丑啊
You know, being a sad,
old, ugly little man.
麻烦来杯啤酒
One gay beer, please.
约会还好吧?
How'd your date go?
我的约会变成暴力事件
My date involved
two instances of
extreme violence.
她握我老二，我用手指插她
One instance of her hand
on my cock and my finger
up her thing,
没玩多久
which lasted all too briefly.
每次都这样吧?
Isn't that always the way?
我偷了她5公克的高档可卡因
One instance of me
stealing five grams of
her very-high-quality cocaine,
还打瞎了一个白痴小混混
and one instance of me
blinding a poofy
little skinhead.
整体而言，今晚还不错
So, all in all,
my evening pretty much
balanced out fine.
你偷了5公克的可卡因?
You got five grams of coke?
身上有4公克，吸了1公克
I've got four grams on me
and one gram in me,
所以我心跳快得像要心脏病发
which is why me heart
is going like the clappers,as if I'm about to
have a heart attack.
如果我昏倒，请你记得要
So if I collapse
any minute now, please
remember to tell the doctors
跟医生说可能是因为可卡因
that it might have something
to do with the coke.
给我1公克
Give us a gram, then.
你不是说吸毒会沮丧?
I thought you were
laying off, because
it makes you depressed?
知道吗?我现在懒得管了
You know what?
Right now, I don't
really give a fuck.
我今天跟你打招呼你怎么不理?
Why didn't you wave
hello to me today when
I waved hello to you today?
我今天吃很多马的镇静剂
I was on a very strong
horse tranquilizer today.
我见到谁都不打招呼
I wasn't waving
hello to anybody,
可能只会搭理马吧
except maybe to a horse.
你在胡说什么?
Huh? What are you
talking about?
他马的废话啦
Just horseshit.
你是美国人?
You from America?
对，别排挤美国人哦
Yeah. But don't
hold it against me.
这要由我决定吧?
Well, that's for me
to decide, isn't it?
你也是美国人?
Are you from America, too?
不是，我从阿姆斯特丹来的
No, I'm from Amsterdam.
阿姆斯特丹?
(SCOFFS) Amsterdam.
阿姆斯特丹不是妓女很多吗?
Amsterdam is just
a load of bloody
prostitutes, isn't it?
对，所以我才来布鲁日
Yes. That's why
I came to Bruges.
来这里卖应该能多赚一点
I thought I'd get
a better price
for my pussy here.
两个怪咖
You two are weird.
要不要可卡因?
Would you like some cocaine?
我还有迷幻药和快乐丸
I've also got some
acid and some ecstasy.
我知道赫夫维勒柴就是自杀的
Herve Villechaize,
I know, did.
危险地带，，的侏儒也自杀
The dwarf off, I think,
The Time Bandits, did.
很多侏儒
Lots of midgets...
小矮人
Dwarves,
都是自杀的
top themselves.
一狗票
Hmm. Shitloads.
你有没有想过?
Would you ever
think about it?
有没有因为你是侏儒而想自杀?
Would you ever think about
killing yourself because
you're a midget?
干！这是什么鸟问题?
Fuck, man!
What kind of
question is that?
只是聊聊天嘛
We're just chatting,
aren't we?
肯尼，你看
See, Ken,
哈利应该帮我们订这种饭店
this is
the kind of hotel
Harry should have put us in.
5星级的，还有妓女
A five-star,
with prostitutes in.
我有时后觉得哈利不在乎我们
You know, sometimes,
I think Harry doesn't even
give a shit about us at all.
他还是没打电话来吗?
Has he still not called?
没有，还是没打
No. Still hasn't called.
没消息就是好消息
No news is good news, eh?
她是谁?
Who's she?
战争要爆发了
JIMMY: There's gonna be
a war, man.
我有预感
I can see it.
黑人和白人之间要开战了
There's gonna be a war
between the blacks
and between the whites.
你根本连制服都不必穿
You ain't even gonna need
a uniform no more.
这场战争你不能选边站
This ain't gonna be a war
where you pick your side.
阵营早就划分好了
Your side's already
picked for you.
我知道我是哪个阵营
And I know whose side
I'm fighting on.
我要和黑人并肩作战
I'm fighting with the blacks.
叫白人去吃大便啦
The whites are gonna get
their heads kicked in!
这种事由不得你决定
JIMMY: You don't decide
this shit, man.
黑白混血儿要站哪一边?
Well, who are
the half-castes
gonna fight with?
当然是跟黑人一起啊
The blacks, man.
That's obvious.
那巴基斯坦人呢?
But what about
the Pakistanis?
黑人
The blacks.
那…
What about...
想个难一点的
Think of a hard one.
那越南人呢?
What about the Vietnamese?
黑人！
The blacks!
有越南人我就一定跟黑人同阵线
Well, I'm definitely
fighting with the blacks
if they've got the Vietnamese.
等一下
So, hang on.
白人侏儒都要和黑人侏儒为敌?
Would all of the
white midgets in
the world be fighting against all the black
midgets in the world?
对
Yeah.
这是拍片的好题材
That would make a good film!
你绝对不会知道
You don't know how much shit
我吃了黑人侏儒多少亏
I've had to take off
of black midgets, man.
这句话…
That's...
…说得对极了
Undeniably true.
吉米…
See, Jimmy,
我老婆是黑人
my wife was black.
我很爱她
And I loved her very much.
1976年
And in 1976,
她被白人杀死了
she was murdered
by a white man.
所以…
So,
这场大屠杀我要站哪一边?
where the fuck
am I supposed to stand
in all this blood and carnage?
有抓到凶手吗?
Did they get
the guy who did it?
我有个朋友抓到他了
A friend of mine got him.
他被哈利华特斯逮到了
Harry Waters got him.
告诉我，吉米
So tell me, Jim,
这场圣战我要站哪一边?
whose side do I fight
on in this wonderful war?
我挛你应该衡量所有的选项
I think you need to
weigh up all your options
让你的良知来决定
and let your
conscience decide, Ken.
两个臭婊子
Two manky hookers
和一个种族歧视的侏儒
and a racist dwarf.
我要回家了
I think I'm heading home.
好，我跟你回去
Yeah. I think
I'll come with you.
怎么…
What's...
闪开啦，矮子！
Back off, shorty!
你又不会空手道
You don't know karate.
你活该啦
Don't say you didn't
have it coming.
你活该啦
Don't say you didn't
have it coming.
好痛
How painful
矮冬瓜！
Shortarse!
我要找尤利
Meeting Yuri.
我就是尤利
Yes, I'm Yuri.
华特斯先生说可能用得上
Mr. Waters said
that might be necessary.
康宁埃斯崔公园有很多暗处可躲
There are a lot of alcoves
in the Koningin Astrid Park.
你会用暗处，，这个词吧?
You use this word,
"alcoves"?
暗处?有时后会用
"Alcoves"? Yes. Sometimes.
圣诞节没什么人会躲在暗处
There are not many
people around in these
alcoves in Christmastime.
我要是想杀人
If I were to murder a man,
就会选在这里
I would murder him here.
你确定可以说暗处，，吗?
Are you sure this is
the right word, "alcoves"?
可以啊
"Alcoves," yes.
就是不显眼的角落
It's kind of like
"nooks and crannies."
对，不显眼的角落
"Nooks and crannies," yes.
这样讲比较正确
Perhaps this would be
more accurate.
不显眼的角落，不是暗处
"Nooks and crannies,"
rather than "alcoves."
对
Yeah.
你会下手吧?
You are going to do it,
aren't you?
不然华特斯先生会很失望…
Mr. Waters
will be very disappointed...
我当然会下手
Of course I'm going to
fucking do it.
这是我的职业
It's what I do.
你朋友今天早上怪怪的
Your friend was behaving
rather oddly this morning.
怎样怪?
Oddly? How?
他问我宝宝的事
Well, he asked me
about the baby,
问我想要男生还是女生
and if
I wanted a boy or a girl.
我说只要健康就好了
I said I didn't mind
as long as it's
healthy, of course.
然后他…
But then
他给了我两百欧元说是要给宝宝
he gave me 200 euros
to give to the baby.
我拒绝了，可是他…
I refused, obviously,
他坚持要我收下
but he was quite insistent.
请你帮我还给他好吗?
Would you give it
back to him when
you see him?
不是我不知感恩
I don't want to appear
ungrateful,
但他好像只剩这些钱
but it seemed
like all the money he had.
你知道他在哪儿吗?
Do you know where he is now?
他说他要去公园
He said he was
going to the park.
雷蒙，对不起
Sorry, Ray.
对不起
I'm sorry.
雷蒙，不要！
Ray, don't!
搞什么?
Fucking hell!
你他妈的从哪儿冒出来的?
Where the fuck
did you come from?
我躲起来啦，你他妈的在干嘛?
I was behind the thing.
What the fuck are
you doing, Ray?
那你又他妈的在干嘛?
What the fuck
are you doing?
没有啊
Nothing.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
天哪！
Oh, my God!
你要杀我
You were gonna kill me.
不是啦，我…
No, I wasn't.
你要自杀
You were gonna
kill yourself!
我…
I
这是我的权利啊
I'm allowed to.
才不是
No, you're not!
怎样?
What?
我不能自杀，你就能杀我?
I'm not allowed to
and you are?
这公平吗?
How's that fair?
能不能找个地方谈谈?
Can we go somewhere
and talk about this, please?
我根本不打算动手
I wasn't gonna go
through with it, Ray.
你看起来就是要动手啊
You fucking looked like
you were gonna go
fucking through with it.
你的枪是哪来的?
Where'd you get that gun?
哈利的朋友
A friend of Harry's.
干！
Fuck, man.
给我看看
Let me see it.
还有消音器
Silencer, too.
不错
Nice.
我的是女生用的枪
Mine's a bloody girl's gun.
给我保管
I'm keeping it.
你说什么?
Pardon me?
把枪还我
Give me me gun back.
我不会还你的
You're not getting it back.
你有自杀倾向
You're a suicide case.
而你想一枪毙了我
And you were
trying to shoot me
in the fucking head.
我不会还你的
You're not getting
that gun back.
我今天运气真好
A great day this has
turned out to be.
我想自杀
I'm suicidal,
我朋友想杀我
me mate tries
to kill me,
我的枪被没收
me gun gets nicked
我们还在布鲁日
and we're still
in fucking Bruges.
听着…
Listen,
我给你一点钱，送你上火车
I'm gonna give you
some money and put you
on a train somewhere.
回英国?
Back to England?
你不能回英国，回去就死定了
You can't go back
to England, Ray.
You'd be a dead man!
肯尼，我想死啊
(CRYING) I want
to be a dead man.
你是不是搞错什么?
Have you been
missing something?
你不想死啦
You don't want to be
a dead man, Ray.
肯尼！
Ken
我杀了一个小男孩
I killed a little boy!
那就不要再犯啊
Then save the
next little boy.
随便去哪里都好
Just go away somewhere,
金盆洗手，做点正当事
get out of this business
and try to do something good.
你死了对谁都没好处
You're not gonna
help anybody dead.
那个小孩不会复活
You're not gonna
bring that boy back.
但你可以不要再犯
But you might save
the next one.
要我做什么?当医生?
What am I gonna be,
a doctor?
那要考试的
You need exams.
随便做什么都好
Do anything, Ray.
做什么都好
Do anything.
(亲爱的肯尼：)
(我去公园，免得她还要清理)
(雷蒙)
他是个大烂人！
RAY: What a wanker!
他说这趟旅程…
He said this whole trip,
这次来布鲁日
this whole being
in Bruges thing,
是要让你在死前开心最后一次
was just to give you
one last, joyful memory
before you died.
在布鲁日?
In Bruges?
去巴哈马群岛还差不多
The Bahamas, maybe.
干嘛挑在布鲁日?
Why fucking Bruges?
大概是比较便宜吧
I suppose it's cheaper.
剩下的迷幻药和快乐丸
The rest of the acid
and the ecstasy.
能不能把枪还我?
Can I have me gun
back, please?
要我做什么?
What am I gonna do, Ken?
我能做什么?
What am I gonna do?
反正你走就对了
Just keep moving.
你走就对了
Keep on moving.
别再想了
Try not to think about it.
也许学个新语言?
Learn a new language, maybe?
对啦，我连英语都讲不好
Sure, I can
hardly do English.
所以我喜欢欧洲
That's one thing
I like about Europe, though.
不必学他们的语言
You don't have to learn
any of their languages.
暂时别回家
Just forget about
home for a while.
看看6，7年后会变成怎样
See how the land lies
in six years, seven years.
7年也没多久啦
Seven years is not that long.
比那个小孩活得久
It's longer than
that boy got.
我他妈的第一次出任务
Me first fucking job.
我真是个好杀手啊
Great hitman
I turned out to be.
有些人就是不适合当杀手
Some people just aren't
cut out for it, Ray.
你适合吗?
Are you?
你几时要回英国?
When are you
going back to England?
我过两个小时就回去了
I'll head back
in a couple of hours
or something.
哈利不会生你的气吧?
Harry's not gonna be
mad at you, is he?
你放我走了?
For letting me go?
哈利那边我会搞定的
I'll sort out Harry.
跟他说我搞不好很快就自杀了
Just tell him I'll have
probably killed meself
in a fortnight, anyway.
你不会吧?
You won't, will you, Ray?
哈利?我是肯尼
Harry? It's Ken.
你听这个声音
Listen to this noise.
你知不知道这是什么?
Do you know what that is?
我知道你听得出这是火车
Yeah, I know
you know it's a train.
你知道什么火车吗?
Do you know what train?
雷蒙刚上这班火车
Well, it's a train that
Ray just got on,
他还活得好好的
and
he's alive and he's well,
他不知道何去何从，我也不知道
and he doesn't know
where he's going
and neither do I.
你想杀我就动手吧
So if you need to
do your worst,
do your worst.
你有旅馆的地址，我在这里等你
You've got the
address of the hotel.
I'll be here waiting.
反正我爱上布鲁日了
Because I've got to quite
like Bruges, now.
他妈的很有童话故事的感觉
It's like a fucking
fairytale or something.
哈利！
Harry.
Harry!
干嘛?
What?
那只是没生命的东西
It's an inanimate
fucking object.
你也是他妈的没生命的东西啦！
You're an inanimate
fucking object!
你们要听妈妈和今本阿姨的话
Now, you lot be good
for your mummy
and lmamoto, okay?
因为爸爸要出差几天
'Cause Daddy's got to
go away for a few days.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
我要去布鲁日
I've got to go to Bruges.
布鲁日?那是哪里?
Bruges? Where's that?
在比利时
It's in Belgium.
去比利时要干嘛?
Why would anybody
have to go to Belgium?
我有事要处理
'Cause I've got to
sort something out.
和电话有关吗?
Is it something
to do with the phone?
和肯尼有关
It's something
to do with Ken.
这是名誉问题
It's a matter of honor.
不会危险吧?
Well, it ain't gonna
be dangerous, is it?
和名誉有关的事他妈的当然危险
Well, of course it's
gonna be dangerous if it's
a matter of fucking honor!
带几个人一起去吧
You are bringing
the fellas with you?
你会带人去吧?
Tell me you're bringing
the fellas with you.
哈利！
Harry.
很抱歉刚才骂你是没生命的东西
I'm sorry for calling you
an inanimate object.
那是气话
I was upset.
你是爱尔兰人?
You're Irish?
对
Yes.
你叫什么名字?
What is your name?
戴瑞波勒里
Derek Perlurrl.
你有答，，加拿大人吗?
You hit the Canadian.
我答，，加拿大人?
L"heet" the Canadian?
我听不懂你在说什么
I don't know what
you're talking about.
就是他！
That's him!
就是那个王八蛋！
That's the motherfucker.
你有答，，加拿大人吧?
You hit the Canadian, yeah?
加拿大人?
Canadian?
干！
Shit.
我们要带你回布鲁日
We're taking you
back to Bruges.
好极了
Brilliant.
真衰啊
Aye aye.
你自己选吧，华特斯先生
YURl: Take your pick,
Mr. Waters.
乌兹?
(CHUCKLES) An Uzi?
我又不从他妈的是洛杉矶中南部来的
I'm not from South Central
Los fucking Angeles.
我不是来扫射20个10岁小孩
I didn't come here to shoot
20 black 10-year-olds
in a fucking drive-by.
我要一般人用的普通手枪
I want a normal gun
for a normal person.
我早知道他不会动手
I knew he wouldn't
kill the guy.
我跟他说暗处时
I could see it in his eyes
看他的眼神就知道了
when I was telling him
about the alcoves.
说什么?
About the what?
The alcoves.
暗处
The alcoves
康宁埃斯崔公园的暗处
in the
Koningin Astrid Park.
我还有达姆弹
Oh, I also have
some dumdums.
是叫达姆弹吧?
You use this word,
"dumdums"?
把头炸掉的那种子弹
The bullets
that make the head explode?
对，达姆弹
Dumdums, yeah.
你要不要达姆弹?
Would you like some
of these dumdums?
我知道我不应该拿
I know I shouldn't,
但我还是拿吧
but I will.
王八蛋！
Motherfucker.
他在跟我讲话吗?
Is he talking to me?
不是，艾瑞克是自己人
No, Eirik's
on your side,
Mr. Waters.
你那位朋友昨晚把他打瞎了
Your young friend
blinded him last night.
是雷蒙?
Ray did?
我想抢劫他
I was trying to rob him
他抢走了我的枪
and he took my gun from me.
那把枪里都是空包弹
And the gun
was full of blanks,
他用空包弹射我的眼睛
and he shot the blank
into my eye.
现在…
And now,
我这只眼睛瞎了
I cannot see
from this eye ever again,
医生说的
the doctors say.
坦白说，你好像是活该
Well, to be honest,
it sounds like
it was all your fault.
什么?
What?
你想抢劫别人，只用空包弹
I mean, basically, if you're
robbing a man and you're
only carrying blanks,
你让别人抢走了你的枪
and you allow your gun
to be taken off you,
又让他用空包弹射你的眼睛
and you allow yourself
to be shot in the
eye with a blank,
对方一定靠你很近吧
for which I assume
the person has to get
quite close to you, then,
你会这么笨就是你活该
yeah, really,
it's all your fault
for being such a poof.
别唉唉叫了，他妈的开心一点嘛
So why don't you
stop whingeing
and cheer the fuck up?
艾瑞克！你最好冷静点
YURl: Eirik, I really
wouldn't respond.
你不是想杀他吗?
I thought you wanted
the guy dead?
我是想杀他，我想他妈把他千刀万剐
I do want the guy dead.
I want him fucking crucified.
但他把你打瞎了
But it don't change the fact
that
这个事实改变不了吧?是吧？
he stitched you up like
a blind, little gay boy.Does it?
谢谢你的枪，尤利
Thanks for the gun, Yuri.
怎样?
Well?
他有自杀倾向，哈利
The boy is suicidal, Harry.
他根本是行尸走肉了
He's a walking dead man.
一直讲地狱和炼狱的事
Keeps going on
about Hell and purgatory...
我昨天打电话给你说什么?
When I phoned you
yesterday, did I ask you,
帮个忙，请你给雷蒙心理谘商?
"Ken, will you do me
a favor and become
Ray's psychiatrist, please?"
不是，我是要你他妈的帮我杀了他
No. What I think I asked you
was, " Could you go blow
his fucking head off for me?"
他有自杀倾向?
"He's suicidal"?
我有自杀倾向，你有自杀倾向
I'm suicidal. You're suicidal.
大家他妈的都有自杀倾向
Everybody's fucking suicidal!
不能一直这样下去
We don't all keep
going on about it!
他自杀了吗?
Has he killed himself yet?
没有嘛，那他就没自杀倾向了
No. So he's not
fucking suicidal, is he?
他早上拿枪抵着头，我阻止了他
He put a loaded gun
to his head this morning.
I stopped him.
什么?他妈的愈来愈离谱了
He... What?
This gets fucking worse!
我们当时在公园
We were down in the park...
先让我搞清楚
Let me get this right.
你们在公园?
You were down in the park?
他妈的这有什么关系?
What's that got to do
with fucking anything?
我先搞清楚，你不只拒绝杀他
Let me get this right.
Not only have you
refused to kill the boy,
他要自杀你还阻止他
you've even stopped the boy
from killing himself,
他自杀就解决了我的问题
which would have
solved my problem,
也解决了你的问题
which would have
solved your problem,
好像也能解决他的问题
which sounds like
it would've solved
the boy's problem.
这样解决不了他的问题
It wouldn't have
solved his problem.
肯尼…
Ken,
要是我杀了小孩
if I had
killed a little kid,
不管是不是故意的
accidentally or otherwise,
我都不会想太多
I wouldn't have
thought twice.
我他妈的当场就会自杀了
I'd have killed myself
on the fucking spot.
On the fucking spot.
他妈的当场就自杀
I'd have stuck
the gun
我他妈的马上就饮弹自尽
in me mouth
on the fucking spot!
那是你，哈利
That's you, Harry.
他还有改变的空间
The boy has the
capacity to change.
他还能过正常人的生活
The boy has the capacity
to do something
decent with his life.
不好意思哦
Excuse me, Ken.
我也有改变的空间
I have the capacity
to change.
对啦
Yeah,
他妈的你只会变得更糟
you do.
You've the capacity
to get fucking worse!
对，终于讲到重点了
Yeah, now I'm
getting down to it!
哈利，面对现实吧
Harry, let's face it.
我不是在说笑，无意冒犯
And I'm not being funny,
I mean no disrespect,
但你很讨人厌
but you're a cunt.
现在讨人厌，一直都讨人厌
You're a cunt now,
you've always been a cunt.
你只会变得更讨人厌
And the only thing that's
gonna change is you're gonna
become an even bigger cunt.
还会多生讨人厌的小孩
Maybe have some
more cunt kids.
别扯我的小孩，干他妈的他们屁事?
Leave my kids
fucking out of it.
What have they done?
他妈的收回你刚才骂我小孩那句的话
You fucking retract that bit
about my cunt fucking kids!
我收回你小孩他妈的讨人厌那句话
I retract that bit about
your cunt fucking kids.
他妈的竟敢侮辱我的小孩！
Insulting my fucking kids!
你太过分了
That's going overboard, mate!
我不是收回了吗?
I retracted it, didn't I?
你还是讨人厌啊
Still leaves you
being a cunt.
我他妈的知道了啦！
Yeah, I fucking got that.
雷蒙人呢?
Where's Ray now?
现在雷蒙有可能在
Oh, right about now,
Ray is in one or other
欧洲本土的任何地方
of the one million towns in
mainland Europe it's possible
to be in,
反正不是这里
other than here.
找到我朋友就还你钱
I'll get all the money
back to you soon as I
get through to me friend.
没关系啦，雷蒙
It's not a problem,
Raymond.
迷幻药和快乐丸我也会还你
And I'll get all your acid
and your ecstasy
back to you, too.
英国式幽默
English humor!
我想你应该带了枪
I'm assuming you've
got your gun on you.
尤里很幽默吧?
That Yuri bloke's
a funny fella, isn't he?
他会做瑜珈
He does yoga.
暗处
"The alcoves."
他讲暗处是什么意思?
Was he going on
to you about the alcoves?
康宁埃斯崔公园有很多暗处可躲
"The alcoves
in the Koningin Astrid Park."
我知道该做的事你就得做
Harry, I know you gotta do
what you gotta do.
但这里人太多了
It's a bit crowded
round here, you know?
他妈的我不会在比利时人群中枪战的
Well, I'm not gonna
have a shootout in the middle of a thousand
fucking Belgians, am I?
更何况还有其他国家的人来渡假
Not to mention
the other nationalities,
just on their holidays.
来看天鹅和哥德式的童话故事
To see the swans
and the Gothic and all
the fairytale stuff, eh?
你想惹毛我吗?
Are you trying to
fucking wind me up?
没有
No, Harry.
你还骂我和我的小孩讨人厌
On top of calling me a cunt
and calling me kids cunts.
他妈的真想现在就毙了你
I might just have to
fucking shoot you right here.
拜托！
Christ!
我们上去钟楼
Let's go up the bell tower.
这么晚了应该很安静
Be quiet up there
this time of evening.
上去吧
Let's go up there.
对，加拿大人
Yeah. Canadians.
我觉得有点难过
I feel a bit bad.
他们没杀约翰蓝侬吧?
They didn't kill
John Lennon, did they?
我再过两天要出庭
Anyway, supposed to turn up
to court here in two days.
你会去吗?
Are you going to turn up?
不知道，我留下来要干嘛?
Don't know.
What have I got to
stay for really?
为了你这无聊的一生
The most beautiful woman
前所未见的…
you've ever seen
…绝世大美女
in all of your stupid life.
今晚钟楼不开放
The tower is closed
this evening.
不可能，应该要开放到7点
No way. It's supposed
to be open till 7:00.
钟楼通常是开放到7点
The tower is usually
open until 7:00.
昨天有个美国人在上面心脏病发
Yesterday an American
had a heart attack
up the tower.
今天钟楼不开放
Today the tower is closed.
怪咖，这一百欧元给你
Here, cranky, here's
100 for you.
我们只上去20分钟
We're only
gonna be 20 minutes.
今晚钟楼…
The tower is closed
…不开放
this evening.
懂吗，英国人?
Understand, Englishman?
吉米…
Jimmy, I've been
wanting to say
我要为那天晚上用手刀劈你道歉
I'm really sorry for
karate-chopping you
the other night.
我太失礼了
That was way out of order.
雷蒙，你知道吗?
You know, Ray,
如果若你们俩不要
I'd find it
easier to believe
他妈的当我的面嘲笑我
and
forgive you, somehow,
我会比较容易相信和原谅你
if the two of you weren't
laughing straight
in my fucking face!
我是来拍电影的啦
It's for the
goddamn movie, man.
这个城市很美，哈利
It is a nice town, Harry.
很高兴我能看得到
I'm glad I got to see it.
我不是故意笑你
I didn't mean to be
taking the piss out of it
说这里像童话故事
being a fairytale place.
这里真的很像童话故事
It is a fairytale place.
真的很像
It really is.
Hmm.
可惜是在比利时
It's just a shame
it's in Belgium, really.
但若不是在比利时
But then you figure
if it wasn't in Belgium,
而是在什么好地方
if it was somewhere good,
就会有很多人来看
there'd be too many people
coming to see it.
把美景都给毁了
It would
spoil the whole thing.
很高兴我能看得到
Well, I'm glad
I got to see it
在我死前
before I died.
你要干嘛?
What are you doing?
你到底他妈的想干嘛?
What are you
fucking doing?
我不想再反抗了
I'm not fighting
anymore, Harry.
好吧，那我他妈的就轰烂你的脑袋
All right, then I'm blowing
your fucking head off.
别学甘地搞和平了
Don't come over all Gandhi.
你他妈的要干嘛?
What are you fucking doing?
请你别闹了，把枪拿起来
Ken, stop messing
about, please.
我知道我横竖要揍你，因为…
Pick up your gun.
I know I'm going
to beat you anyway
哈利…
'Cause you're a spaz, but...
Harry,
我欠你人情
I'm totally in your debt.
你过去对我的恩情
The things that have
gone between us in the past,
我感激你一辈子
I love you
unreservedly
for all that.
什么?
What?
你的正直
For your integrity.
你的荣誉感
For your honor.
我爱你
I love you.
我非放他走不可
The boy had to be let go.
要给他一次机会
The boy had to be
given a chance.
如果放过他
And if to do that,
就表示我背叛你
I had to say,
不顾你对我的恩情
" Fuck you,
and fuck what I owe you,
不顾我们之间的过去
"and fuck everything
that's gone on between us,"
那我还是非做不可
then that's what I had to do.
但我不会反抗你
But I'm not fighting you.
不管你怎么做我都接受
And I accept, totally,
everything you've got to do.
我完全接受
I accept it. Totally.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
对
Yeah.
你他妈的说了这些话就
Well, you say all that
fucking stuff,
我他妈的我不能杀你了
I can't
fucking shoot you now, can I?
由你决定，哈利
It's entirely
up to you, Harry.
由你决定
It's entirely your call.
我只想说…
All I'm saying is
我不反抗了
I'm not fighting.
你他妈的这个王八蛋！
Oh, you fucking cunt!
你像罗伯包尔一样站在那儿
Look, I'm not gonna
do nothing to you
我就不会对你怎样吗?
just 'Cause you're
standing about like
Robert fucking Powell.
像谁?
Like who?
拿撒勒的耶稣里的罗伯包尔
Like Robert fucking Powell out of Jesus of
fucking Nazareth!
我的腿！
My fucking leg!
疯子侏儒变成可爱的小学生了
The psycho dwarf
turns out to just be
a loveable little schoolboy,
像波许画作中的噩梦一样
and it's all some kind of
Boschian nightmare.
去你的！
Kiss my ass!
至少和黑人无关吧，吉米?
I guess at least there
weren't any black people
involved, eh, Jimmy?
我不是…
I wasn't...
我指的不是…
I wasn't talking about...
黑人和白人之间要开战了
There's gonna be a war
between all the blacks
and all the whites.
黑人侏儒和白人侏儒也要开战
And all the black midgets
and all the white midgets,
这下可精彩了
which would actually
be really good.
我是嗑药乱讲的啦
That's just cocaine.
他不要和越南人同一阵营
He didn't even want
the Vietnamese on his side!
我是嗑药乱讲的啦
That's just cocaine.
我们今晚要去尖顶建筑拍片
Listen, we're filming
down by the pointy
building tonight.
搞不好这次会很顺利
It might actually be
good for once.
欢迎你们来看
You guys should come along.
我们…
We...
我们今晚想安静地独处
I think we're just
gonna have a quiet one
tonight, Jimmy.
原来如此啊
That's how it is!
下辈子吧
In another life.
侏儒很棒吧?
They're great,
aren't they?
你有啦
You didn't.
你有
You didn't!
华特斯先生?
Mr. Waters?
你是谁?
Who's that?
我是艾瑞克
It's Eirik.
瞎了眼的那个?
The blind boy?
对
Yeah.
Yes.
你他妈的要干嘛?
What do you fucking want?
你在找的那雷蒙
The guy you're looking for,the guy Ray,
他在楼下的酒吧
he's downstairs
at the bar.
对不起，肯尼
I'm sorry, Ken.
但杀死小孩就不能苟活在世上
But you can't kill
a kid and expect to
get away with it.
就是不行
You just can't.
在哪里?
Where?
下去之后往左边
To the left when you come out.
在左边的酒吧
The bar to the left.
在秋日的雷格伦路上
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
我先看到她
我知道…
她的黑发会编成陷阱
也许我将来会懊悔
我看到危险也躲过了
在美不胜收的路上
我说过让悲伤
像落叶似地飘落
在一天的开始
11月天在葛拉夫顿街上
我们在深峻的峡谷
轻步走在岩棚的边缘
热情价值有多高
红心女王还在做馅饼
我没什么收获
我爱得太深
就这样…
抛弃了幸福
当天使求爱时
他将惨遭滑铁卢
他的双翼在黎明时分
肯尼?
Ken!
肯尼！
哈利来了
Harry's here.
什么?
What?
拿着…
Take
…我的枪
my gun.
肯尼?
Ken?
我的枪呢?
Where's my gun?
我要死了
I'm gonna die now,
应该吧
I think.
肯尼！
Oh, Ken!
天哪！
Jesus!
布雷克利先生说你走了
Mr. Blakely said
you had left.
快给我房间的钥匙
I need the key
to the room right now.
快点！马上给我！
Quickly, now!
你快回家，这里非常危险
And you gotta go
home right now. It's very,
very dangerous here.
好
All right?
回家去！快点！
Go home!
Right now!
好
Okay.
(肯尼的旅馆)
(我的遗嘱)
不行，我不能让你上去
MARIE: No, I won't let you
up there!
马上把枪收起来
Put that
gun away, right now!
小姐，请你让开
HARRY: Lady, get out of
my fucking way, please.
我不要
No, I won't.
我不要让开
I won't
get out of your way.
你要先通过我这一关
You'll have to
go through me.
我不能对你怎样，你身怀六甲
Well, obviously,
I'm not gonna through you,
am I, with a baby and that?
我是好人，但请你让开好吗?
I'm a nice person.
But could you just get out
of the fucking way, please?
玛莉?
Marie!
让他上来，没关系
Just let him
come up, it's okay.
哈利?
Harry,
请发誓你会等她走出旅馆再开枪
swear not to
start shooting until
she's left the hotel.
我会等她走出旅馆再开枪
I swear not to start shooting
till she's left the hotel.
我对天发誓
I totally swear.
我哪儿也不去
Well, I'm not
going anywhere.
这是我的旅馆
This is my hotel.
请你滚！
So you can fuck off!
你应该有枪吧?
I suppose you've got
a gun up there?
有
Yeah.
怎么办?不能在这里站一整夜啊
Then what are we gonna do?
We can't stand here all night.
你们俩都把枪放下回家去吧
Why don't you both
put your guns down
and go home?
别傻了
Don't be stupid.
我们要枪战
This is the shootout.
哈利?
Harry,
我有个办法
I've got an idea.
什么办法?
What?
我的房间是面对运河的
My room faces
onto the canal, right?
我现在回房间，跳进运河
I'm gonna go back to me room,
jump into the canal,
看看我能不能游到对岸逃走
see if I can swim
to the other side
and escape.
好
Right.
你现在走出去，绕过街角
If you go outside
and round the corner,
从那里开枪，想办法抓到我
you can shoot at me
from there and try
and get me.
这样就不会伤到他们母女了
That way, we leave this lady
and her baby out of
the whole, entire thing.
你真的会跳进运河吗?
Do you completely promise
to jump into the canal?
我不想跑出去10分钟后回来
I don't want to
run out there,
come back in 10 minutes
发现你他妈的躲在碗橱里
and find you fucking
hiding in a cupboard.
我跟你保证
I completely promise, Harry.
我不想再害死另一个小孩
I'm not gonna risk
having another
little kid die, am I?
等一下，我出去要左转还右转?
So, hang on, I go outside,
then I go which way,
right or left?
你要右转
You go right,
don't you?
站在门口就看得到，他妈的运河很大
You can see it
from the doorway!
It's a big fucking canal!
好啦！真是的！我才刚来嘛！
All right. Jesus!
I've only just
got here, haven't I?
好，数到3就开始动作
Okay. On a count of
"one, two, three, go," okay?
好
Okay.
怎样?谁来数?
What? Who says it?
你来数
Oh, you say it.
你们都疯了
You guys are crazy.
准备好了吗?
Are you ready?
好了
Ready.
预备?
Set?
预备
Set.
1，2，3，开始！
One, two, three, go!
继续开船
Keep driving!
不可能，你距离太远了
No way. You're way
too far away.
小男孩
The little boy.
对，雷蒙
That's right, Ray.
小男孩
The little boy.
我懂了
I see.
哈利，别开枪
No, Harry.
他不是…
He's not...
做人要坚守原则
You've got to stick
to your principles.
伦敦有棵圣诞树底下堆满了礼物
RAY. ; There's a Christmas tree
somewhere in London with a bunch of presents
永远不会被拆开
underneath it that'll
never be opened.
我想只要我能活下去
And I thought,
"If I survive all this,
我就要回去那个家
I'll go to that house,
向我的母亲道歉
"apologize to
the mother there,
不管她要怎么惩罚我都接受
"and accept whatever
punishment she chose for me."
监狱
Prison,
死亡，都无所谓
death,
it didn't matter.
因为至少坐牢和死掉
Because at least in prison
and at least in death,
you know,
我都不会在他妈的布鲁日
I wouldn't be
in fucking Bruges.
但种种景象掠过我眼前
But then, like a flash,
it came to me,
我才发觉…
and I realized,
靠！也许这就是地狱
"Fuck, man, maybe
that's what Hell is.
他妈的在布鲁日待到天荒地老
"The entire rest of eternity
spent in fucking Bruges!"
我真的很希望我不会死
And I really, really
hoped I wouldn't die.
我真的很希望我不会死
I really, really
hoped I wouldn't die.